The Mainprice Deposit
The Mainprice Deposit
- Documents relating to Lancashire and Cheshire, 1564-1809; GB/418/F.1.1-20 & F.2.1-12; GB/418/Main/5; 632 files; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Southport, 1746 & 1856; GB/418/S3-S5; GB/418/Main/5/58; 3 files; Chetham's Library
    - Release of the legacy of Sarah Harrison, 8 Aug 1856; GB/418/S3; GB/418/Main/5/58/1; Chetham's Library
      From George Thomas and Mary Ann Whitgrave of Eaton Square, co Midd to Charles Clough of Southport and William Sandford of Bath
    - Deed concerning uses of fine relating to land in Spotland, Castleton, Butterworth, Hundersfield and Rochdale, 10 Jul 1746; GB/418/S4; GB/418/Main/5/58/2; Chetham's Library
      From Nicholas Shuttleworth, gent and Sarah his wife of Castleton to William Ingham of Rochdale, mercer and Edward Lord of Rochdale, clothier
    - Final concord at Lancaster concerning land in Spotland, Castleton, Butterworth, Hundersfield and Rochdale, 30 Jul 1746; GB/418/S5; GB/418/Main/5/58/3; Chetham's Library
      Between Edmund Lord and John Kershaw, plaintiffs, Nicholas Shuttleworth, Sarah his wife, John Stott and Mary his wife, deforciants
  - Document relating to Stockport, 1807; GB/418/S6; GB/418/Main/5/59; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Mortgage of land in Stockport, 5 Feb 1807; GB/418/S6; GB/418/Main/5/59/1; Chetham's Library
      From Joseph and Mary Ingham of Great Lever to James Ingham of Salford
  - Documents relating to Stretford, 1705-1808; GB/418/S7-S26; GB/418/Main/5/60; 20 files; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Stretford, 4 Sep 1705; GB/418/S7; GB/418/Main/5/60/1; Chetham's Library
      From William Rogers of Stretford to Richard Harrison alias Hughs of Stretford
    - Conveyance of land in Stretford, 20 Mar 1724; GB/418/S8; GB/418/Main/5/60/2; Chetham's Library
      From Francis Johnson of Stretford, carrier, to Joshua Taylor of London, warehouseman
    - Mortgage of land in Stretford, 4 May 1753; GB/418/S9; GB/418/Main/5/60/3; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Lightbown of Stretford, yeoman, to Thomas Walton of Dunham Massey, gent
    - Will of Thomas Lightbown of Stretford, yeoman, 8 Feb 1756; GB/418/S10; GB/418/Main/5/60/4; Chetham's Library
    - Assignment of land in Stretford, 13 Mar 1760; GB/418/S11; GB/418/Main/5/60/5; Chetham's Library
      From James Moores of Stretford to James Moss of Broughton
    - Bond in £400 to perform covenants, 15 Mar 1760; GB/418/S12; GB/418/Main/5/60/6; Chetham's Library
      From James Moores of Stretford, yeoman to James Moss of Broughton, yeoman
    - Assignment of land in Stretford, 8 Aug 1764; GB/418/S13; GB/418/Main/5/60/7; Chetham's Library
      From James Moores of Stretford to Thomas Strettell of Chorlton and William Chadwick of Stretford
    - Conditions of sale of a property in Stretford, 24 Oct 1765; GB/418/S14; GB/418/Main/5/60/8; Chetham's Library
    - Lease of land in Stretford, 12 Nov 1766; GB/418/S15; GB/418/Main/5/60/9; Chetham's Library
      From Humphrey Trafford of Trafford to William Higginbotham of Manchester
    - Sale of assignment of tenement in Stretford, 1 Jan 1769; GB/418/S16; GB/418/Main/5/60/10; Chetham's Library
      From Countess of Stamford to John Johnson of Stretford et al
    - Assignment of lease of land in Stretford, 10 Feb 1769; GB/418/S17; GB/418/Main/5/60/11; Chetham's Library
      From Edward Stelfox of Dunham Massey to Richard Pearson of Chorlton
    - Assignment of lease of land in Stretford, 4 Jan 1770; GB/418/S18; GB/418/Main/5/60/12; Chetham's Library
      From John Johnson of Stretford et al to Richard Pearson of Chorlton
    - Will of Edmund Rigby of Stretford, 24 Apr 1771; GB/418/S19; GB/418/Main/5/60/13; Chetham's Library
    - Lease of land in Stretford, 29 Oct 1795; GB/418/S20; GB/418/Main/5/60/14; Chetham's Library
      From John Trafford Esq of Rolleston, Staffs to Sir John Parker Mosley and John Lingard
    - Lease of land in Stretford, 22 Jul 1800; GB/418/S21; GB/418/Main/5/60/15; Chetham's Library
      From James Bradshaw of Stretford to William Bradshaw of Stretford
    - Final concord at Lancaster concerning land in Stretford, 19 Mar 1803; GB/418/S22; GB/418/Main/5/60/16; Chetham's Library
      Between James Cooke plaintiff, William Mosley Higginbotham and Sarah his wife, deforciants
    - Lease of estate in Stretford, 24 Sep 1804; GB/418/S23; GB/418/Main/5/60/17; Chetham's Library
      From John Trafford to James Cooke of Stretford
    - Will of Peter Fazackerly of Stretford, farmer, 27 Jan 1808; GB/418/S24; GB/418/Main/5/60/18; Chetham's Library
    - Lease of land in Stretford, 22 Dec 1808; GB/418/S25; GB/418/Main/5/60/19; Chetham's Library
      From Colonel John Drinkwater of Kensington to Robert Barlow of Manchester
    - Plan of an estate in Stretford, 19th century; GB/418/S26; GB/418/Main/5/60/20; Chetham's Library
  - Documents relating to Swinton, 1809-1835; GB/418/S27-S29; GB/418/Main/5/61; 3 files; Chetham's Library
    - Lease of land in Swinton, 5 May 1809; GB/418/S27; GB/418/Main/5/61/1; Chetham's Library
      From Daniel Dorning of Swinton to Lydia Scholes of Swinton
    - Probate of will of Elias Chadwick of Swinton, 24 Mar 1825; GB/418/S28; GB/418/Main/5/61/2; Chetham's Library
    - Lease of coal mine in Swinton, 24 Jun 1835; GB/418/S29; GB/418/Main/5/61/3; Chetham's Library
      From Elias Chadwick of Swinton to Andrew Knowles of Little Bolton, coal merchant
  - Document relating to Tyldesley, 1789; GB/418/F.1.20 (T1); GB/418/Main/5/62; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Final concord at Lancaster of land in Tyldesley, 14 Aug 1789; GB/418/F.1.20 (T1); GB/418/Main/5/62/1; Chetham's Library
      Between Thomas Worthington, plaintiff, and Jonathan and Ann Rogerson, deforciants
  - Document relating to Whitefield, 1790; GB/418/F.1.20 (W1); GB/418/Main/5/63; 1 file; Chetham's Library
    - Release of land in Whitefield, 2 Nov 1790; GB/418/F.1.20 (W1); GB/418/Main/5/63/1; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Hampson of Pilkington and [?Horrocks] of Pilkington to Joseph Cross of Manchester, corn dealer
  - Documents relating to Wigan, 1608-1783; GB/418/F.1.20 (W2-W20); GB/418/Main/5/64; 16 files; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in the Mylnegate in Wigan, 10 Sep 1608; GB/418/F.1.20 (W2); GB/418/Main/5/64/1; Chetham's Library
      From Myles Gerrard of Ince in Makerfield to Oliver Baron of Wigan
    - Conveyance of land in Wigan, 6 Jul 1618; GB/418/F.1.20 (W3, W4 & W5); GB/418/Main/5/64/2; 3 items; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Gerrard of Ince in Makerfield to Hugh Forth of Wigan
    - Conveyance of land in Wigan, 20 Aug 1678; GB/418/F.1.20 (W6); GB/418/Main/5/64/3; Chetham's Library
      Left side of document cut away leaving incomplete text
      From Thomas Leyland of Wigan, haberdasher to John Leyland of Haigh
    - Conveyance of land in Wigan, 30 Sep 1706; GB/418/F.1.20 (W7); GB/418/Main/5/64/4; Chetham's Library
      From Ralph Barton of Wigan, blacksmith, to Margaret Fairhurst of Wigan, widow
    - Conveyance of land in Wigan, 22 Jul 1710; GB/418/F.1.20 (W8); GB/418/Main/5/64/5; Chetham's Library
      From Lightbown family of Manchester, Robert Gartside of Manchester et al to Henry Bullock
    - Bond in £220 to perform covenants in a deed, 22 Jul 1710; GB/418/F.1.20 (W9); GB/418/Main/5/64/6; Chetham's Library
    - Will of Henry Bullock of Wigan, linenweaver, 2 Sep 1710; GB/418/F.1.20 (W10); GB/418/Main/5/64/7; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Wigan, 13 May 1726; GB/418/F.1.20 (W11); GB/418/Main/5/64/8; Chetham's Library
      From Robert Mosse of Wigan, blacksmith, to Ellen Bancker of Duxbury, spinster
    - Conveyance of land in Wigan, 30 Jan 1728; GB/418/F.1.20 (W12); GB/418/Main/5/64/9; Chetham's Library
      From Henry Bullock of Wigan, linenweaver, to Ralph Wilson of Wigan
    - Conveyance of land in Wigan, 29 Jan 1730; GB/418/F.1.20 (W13); GB/418/Main/5/64/10; Chetham's Library
      From Henry Bullock of Wigan, linenweaver, to Robert Holt of Wigan
    - Inchoate conveyance of land in Wigan, 1732-1733; GB/418/F.1.20 (W14); GB/418/Main/5/64/11; Chetham's Library
      From Henry Bullock of Wigan to Robert Holt of Wigan and Ralph Wilson of Wigan
    - Lease and release of land in Wigan, 1 & 2 Feb 1733; GB/418/F.1.20 (W15 & W16); GB/418/Main/5/64/12; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From Henry Bullock of Wigan, linenweaver, to Ralph Banks of Salford, gent
    - Conveyance of Page Fields in Wigan in trust for the poor, 29 Dec 1763; GB/418/F.1.20 (W17); GB/418/Main/5/64/13; Chetham's Library
      From William Curghey of Swinley in Wigan, gent, to Ralph Earle of Liverpool, merchant, John Markland of Manchester, merchant et al
    - Conveyance of Page Fields in Wigan in trust for the poor, 8 Dec 1778; GB/418/F.1.20 (W18); GB/418/Main/5/64/14; Chetham's Library
      Very stained and faded
      From Ralph Earle of Liverpool, merchant, John Markland of Manchester, merchant, to Rev Guy Fairfax, rector of Wigan
    - Bond in £300 to execute conveyance of lands in Wigan, 15 Jul 1783; GB/418/F.1.20 (W19); GB/418/Main/5/64/15; Chetham's Library
      From William Barrow of Salford, merchant to Elias Chadwick of Wigan, merchant
    - Articles of agreement concerning lease of Page Fields in Wigan, 2 Dec 1783; GB/418/F.1.20 (W20); GB/418/Main/5/64/16; Chetham's Library
      Between John Markland of Manchester, esq, Rev Guy Fairfax, rector of Wigan, Alexander Radcliffe of Ormskirk, esq, Elias Chadwick of Wigan, cotton merchant and Margaret Williams of Wigan, widow.
  - Documents relating to Winton, 1812 & 1815; GB/418/F.1.20 (W21-W24); GB/418/Main/5/65; 3 files; Chetham's Library
    - Lease of farm in Winton, 18 Apr 1812; GB/418/F.1.20 (W21 & W22); GB/418/Main/5/65/1; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From John Lomax of Manchester to George Timperley of Winton
    - Assignment of farm in Winton, 7 Sep 1812; GB/418/F.1.20 (W23); GB/418/Main/5/65/2; Chetham's Library
      From George Timperley of Winton to James Bowker of Winton
    - Agreement concerning land in Winton, 14 Oct 1815; GB/418/F.1.20 (W24); GB/418/Main/5/65/3; Chetham's Library
      Between George Timperley of Dunham Massey and James Lomax of Barton-upon-Irwell
  - Documents relating to Worsley, 1729-1815; GB/418/F.1.20 (W25-W27); GB/418/Main/5/66; 3 files; Chetham's Library
    - Will of Robert Cooke of Worsley, yeoman, 6 Aug 1729; GB/418/F.1.20 (W25); GB/418/Main/5/66/1; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of land in Worsley, 17 Nov 1786; GB/418/F.1.20 (W26); GB/418/Main/5/66/2; Chetham's Library
      From Giles Hardman of Clifton to Jane Boardman of Clifton
    - General release for residuary legatees under will of Mary Grundy of Worsley, 31 Aug 1815; GB/418/F.1.20 (W27); GB/418/Main/5/66/3; Chetham's Library
  - Deeds concerning Lancashire and Cheshire (place unspecified), 1722-1838; GB/418/F.1.20 (X1-X14); GB/418/Main/5/67; 12 files; Chetham's Library
    - Conveyance of lands in many parts of Lancashire, 4 Apr 1722; GB/418/F.1.20 (X1); GB/418/Main/5/67/1; Chetham's Library
      From John Gooden of Barton and Thomas Gooden of Barton to Roger Bolton, fellow of Manchester Collegiate Church
    - Agreement concerning house and land, 18 Oct 1752; GB/418/F.1.20 (X2); GB/418/Main/5/67/2; Chetham's Library
      Between Elizabeth Fletcher, John Cooke and James Ashworth
    - Release of lands in parts of Cheshire, 7 Jul 1763; GB/418/F.1.20 (X3); GB/418/Main/5/67/3; Chetham's Library
      From Thomas Cooper to James Etchells
    - Deed to declare uses of a fine of lands in Lancashire, 1 Mar 1769; GB/418/F.1.20 (X4 & X5); GB/418/Main/5/67/4; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From Johnson Atkinson of Bingley and Elizabeth his wife to Rev Timothy Lowton of Davyhulme and James Shawcross of Bent Lane in Barton
    - Conveyance of land in Lancashire, 12 May 1769; GB/418/F.1.20 (X6); GB/418/Main/5/67/5; Chetham's Library
      From William Williamson of Rooden Lane in Prestwich to John Birch of Pendleton et al
    - Notes concerning disputed ownership of a pew, Early 18th century; GB/418/F.1.20 (X7); GB/418/Main/5/67/6; Chetham's Library
    - Lease and release of land in Lancashire and elsewhere, 12 & 13 Jul 1813; GB/418/F.1.20 (X8 & X9); GB/418/Main/5/67/7; 2 items; Chetham's Library
      From Samuel Taylor Esq of Moston to Thomas and John Hutchinson of Bury
    - Case concerning title to land in Lancashire, 7 Nov 1831; GB/418/F.1.20 (X10); GB/418/Main/5/67/8; Chetham's Library
    - Case concerning title to lands [?in Lancashire], 18 Nov 1831; GB/418/F.1.20 (X11); GB/418/Main/5/67/9; Chetham's Library
    - Affidavit and pedigree of Rev George Bingham of Kingston Seymour, clerk, 28 Mar 1832; GB/418/F.1.20 (X12); GB/418/Main/5/67/10; Chetham's Library
    - Account from Thomas N Chubb, solicitor, Apr 1832; GB/418/F.1.20 (X13); GB/418/Main/5/67/11; Chetham's Library
    - Appointment by surviving trustee under settlement of Mr and Mrs Samuel Mee of William Gould as a trustee and assignment of trust monies, 6 & 7 Apr 1838; GB/418/F.1.20 (X14); GB/418/Main/5/67/12; Chetham's Library
- Documents relating to counties other than Lancashire and Cheshire, 16th century-19th century; GB/418/F.2.1-F.2.12; GB/418/Main/6; 249 files; Chetham's Library
  These documents have not been listed but have been arranged according to the county they relate to.
  - Documents relating to Essex, 1680-1766; GB/418/F.2.1; GB/418/Main/6/1; 14 files; Chetham's Library
    14 deeds. Unlisted.
  - Documents relating to Hertfordshire, 1623-1834; GB/418/F.2.2 & F.2.3; GB/418/Main/6/2; 52 files; Chetham's Library
    Mostly concerning Bishop's Stortford. Unlisted.
    The documents have been sorted into 2 bundles, one containing 29 deeds (1623-1748), and the other containing 23 deeds (1757-1834).
  - Documents relating to Kent, 1678-1837; GB/418/F.2.4; GB/418/Main/6/3; 10 files; Chetham's Library
    10 deeds. Unlisted.
  - Documents relating to London, 1656-1733; GB/418/F.2.5; GB/418/Main/6/4; 16 files; Chetham's Library
    16 deeds. Unlisted.
  - Documents relating to Middlesex, 1645-1827; GB/418/F.2.6 & F.2.7; GB/418/Main/6/5; 57 files; Chetham's Library
    Unlisted. The documents have been sorted into 2 bundles, one containing 37 deeds (1645-1699), and one contianing 20 deeds (1701-1827).
  - Documents relating to Nottinghamshire, 1808; GB/418/F.2.8; GB/418/Main/6/6; 8 files; Chetham's Library
    8 deeds. Unlisted.
  - Documents relating to Staffordshire, 1654-1865; GB/418/F.2.9; GB/418/Main/6/7; 29 files; Chetham's Library
    29 deeds. Unlisted.
    Includes records of Sedgeley Manor Court, 1650s.
  - Documents relating to Berkshire and Norfolk, 17th century-19th century; GB/418/F.2.10; GB/418/Main/6/8; 19 files; Chetham's Library
    19 deeds. Unlisted.
  - Documents relating to Oxfordshire and Yorkshire, 16th century-19th century; GB/418/F.2.11; GB/418/Main/6/9; 22 files; Chetham's Library
    22 deeds. Unlisted.
  - Miscellaneous documents, 17th century-18th century; GB/418/F.2.12; GB/418/Main/6/10; 22 files; Chetham's Library
    Consists of 11 final concords and 11 other deeds relating to various places including Australia, Belgium and New Zealand.